chemindustry.com 2003-06-24

# ChemIndustry.com Privacy Policy

**Privacy Statement for ChemIndustry.com**

ChemIndustry.com has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the ChemIndustry.com Web site. 

**Information We Collect**

ChemIndustry.com tracks visitors to the site. Through tracking, we can gather statistics that help us customize information, and therefore meet our users' needs. Note: when analyzing these statistics we do not ascertain the individual identity of a ChemIndustry.com user. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is used to gather broad demographic information only. We use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests. We also use cookies for other purposes such as determining how often in the aggregate our users visit the site. When analyzing our traffic, ChemIndustry.com also looks at where our users have been referred from (the last URL you visited before coming to ChemIndustry.com), your domain (e.g. aol.com, or microsoft.com), and what kind of browser and operating system you're using. 

**Information You Supply**

Use of ChemIndustry.com is free and does not require that you register with us. ChemIndustry.com also offers premium services to those that do provide us with specific information. These services include adding your site to our database, submitting a free classified ad, use of our "Ask the Expert" feature, receiving one of our newsletters, and other services we may add. 

Our site's registration form requires users to give us contact information, i.e. name and email address. We use this contact information from the registration form to send the user information about our company and to contact you if necessary to facilitate your entry into our database. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings (see the choice/opt-out section below). We also ask for information such as job title and location to better understand the types of visitors to ChemIndustry.com so that we can provide relevant content for our users. We share only aggregate summaries of this data with our business partners and will not disclose any specific user information or email addresses with anyone outside the company.

Our online surveys ask visitors for contact information, i.e. their email address. Specific survey responses are kept confidential and only aggregate summaries are shared with business partners and third parties. We run contests on our site from time to time in which we ask entrants for contact information, i.e. their email address. We use contact data from our contests to send users information about our company. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings (see the choice/opt-out section below). We also ask for information such as job title and location to better understand the types of visitors to ChemIndustry.com so that we can provide relevant content for our users. Address information collected for the contests will be used to ship any prizes or premiums.

**ChemIndustry.com does not sell or give away any personal information you supply and we take responsible security measures to protect the information.**

**Public Forums**

This site makes classified ads available to its users. Please remember that any information disclosed in these areas becomes public information, therefore caution should be exercised when deciding to disclose your personal information.

**External Links**

This site contains links to other sites. **ChemIndustry.com** is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

**Security**

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. At this time there are no services on ChemIndustry.com that would require your credit card number, social security number, or other such identifying information.

**Choice/Opt-Out**

This site gives users the following options for removing their personal information from our database or to not receive future communications from ChemIndustry.com.

  1. You can send email to [customerservice@chemindustry.com](mailto:customerservice@chemindustry.com)
  2. You can visit the following URL: [www.chemindustry.com/mail](http://www.chemindustry.com/mail)
  3. You can send mail to the postal address provided below.

This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided.

  1. Email [customerservice@chemindustry.com](mailto:customerservice@chemindustry.com)
  2. You can send mail to the postal address provided below.

**Contacting the Web Site**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact:

© 2000 ChemIndustry.com Rev 1.0 2/14/2000
